Finding Aid for the Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2002
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo, 2002
Mus. Arc. 20
Haupt, Irene
1 box (28 photographs)
State University of New York at Buffalo. Music Library
Contains 28 photographs of musicians who participated in the June in Buffalo Festival 2002 at the University at Buffalo.
Administrative Information
Terms of Access
Materials can be examined by qualified researchers in the Music Library during hours of operation during which Music Librarians are present. In order to insure access, researchers are advised to contact the Music Library in advance of visits.
Acquisition Information
Purchased from Irene Haupt, 2003.
Accruals and Additions
No further accruals are expected to this collection.
Alternate Forms
All images are available in the UB Libraries Digital Collections as part of the overall June in Buffalo Collection.
Biographical Note
Irene Haupt, a graduate of the State University of New York at Buffalo, has been documenting the Buffalo arts scene through her photography since 1976. During that time she has worked for, or with, some of the most notable institutions in Buffalo, including the Irish Classical Theatre, Studio Arena Theater, the Kavinoky Theatre, the Buffalo Philharmonic Orchestra, the Theatre of Youth, the Albright-Knox Art Gallery, and the State University of New York at Buffalo. In addition to her specialty of theater photography, Irene Haupt has also devoted much of her career to the photography of musicians and musical events. Most notable is her documentation of the contemporary music scene in Buffalo, including coverage of the University at Buffalo's June in Buffalo festival of new music, 1982-1987, and 2000 to the present. Over the course of those years, she has created a visual record that contains images of some of the most significant composers and performers of the last quarter century. The list of names is impressive: Aaron Copland, Morton Feldman, Leo Smit, Virgil Thomson, Steve Reich, Ralph Shapey, Henry Brant, Earle Brown, Ursula Oppens, Jan Williams, Lukas Foss, Philip Glass, Otto Luening, Conlon Nancarrow, Ernst Krenek, Larry Austin, Lejaren Hiller, Elliott Carter, Milton Babbitt, John Cage, Charles Wuorinen, Jacob Druckman, and Yvar Mikhashoff, among others.
The June in Buffalo festival of contemporary music was begun at the University at Buffalo in 1975 by composer Morton Feldman. He directed the festival 1975-1978 and in 1980. The festival was dormant from 1981 through 1985. David Felder revived the festival in 1986 and has been its director since that time.
Scope and Content Note
The collection of Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2002 contains 28 images of participants in the festival for 2002. The list of musicians includes Tony Arnold, John Harbison, Jonathan Harvey, Philippe Manoury, Bernard Rands, Magnus Martensson, James Primosch, and Augusta Read Thomas.
Arrangement
One sequence of images in alphabetical order by principal subject of the image.
Container List
- Photographs, June 2002, I.
  - Tony Arnold, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 1)
  - Tony Arnold, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 2)
  - Tony Arnold, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 3)
  - Jonathan Golove, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 4)
  - Jonathan Golove, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 5)
  - Jonathan Golove, Stephen Manes, Cheryl Gobbetti-Hoffman, and Tamar Muskal, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 6)
  - John Harbison, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 7)
  - John Harbison and David Felder, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 8)
  - Bernard Rands, John Harbison, and David Felder, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 9)
  - Bernard Rands, John Harbison, and David Felder, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 10)
  - Jonathan Harvey during lecture, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 11)
  - Jonathan Harvey, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 12)
  - Jonathan Harvey and Magnus Martensson, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 13)
  - Jonathan Harvey and Tony Arnold, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 14)
  - Jonathan Harvey, Magnus Martensson, and Tony Arnold, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 15)
  - Jonathan Harvey, Magnus Martensson, and Tony Arnold, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 16)
  - Jonathan Harvey and Ian Pace, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 17)
  - Philippe Manoury and Meridian Arts Ensemble, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 18)
  - Philippe Manoury, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 19)
  - Philippe Manoury, Magnus Martensson, and Ian Pace, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 20)
  - Philippe Manoury and Ian Pace, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 21)
  - Magnus Martensson, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 22)
  - Magnus Martensson and David Felder, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 23)
  - Magnus Martensson, Ian Pace, and Slee Sinfonietta, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 24)
  - James Primosch, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 25)
  - James Primosch and Jean Kopperud, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 26)
  - Bernard Rands, composer, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 27)
  - Bernard Rands, June 2002, 1 black and white photograph, 8 x 10 inches (Box 1, Item 28)
Search Terms
The following terms have been used to index the description of this collection in the Library's online catalog.
Subjects
June in Buffalo (Festival) (Buffalo, N.Y.)--Photographs; Composers--Photographs; Music festivals--New York (State)--Buffalo--Photographs; Musicians--Photographs
Genres
Photographs; Portraits
Associated Material
Related Resources
Related Resources in the Music Library
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2000
Mus. Arc. 18
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2000 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2001
Mus. Arc. 19
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2001 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2003
Mus. Arc. 21
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2003 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2004
Mus. Arc. 25
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2004 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2005
Mus. Arc. 27
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2005 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2006
Mus. Arc. 29
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2006 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2007
Mus. Arc. 38
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2007 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2008
Mus. Arc. 39
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2008 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2009
Mus. Arc. 50
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2009 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2010
Mus. Arc. 55
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2010 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2011
Mus. Arc. 56
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2011 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2012
Mus. Arc. 60
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2012 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2013
Mus. Arc. 66
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2013 June in Buffalo.
Irene Haupt Photographs of June in Buffalo 2014
Mus. Arc. 67
Finding aid for collection of photographs for 2014 June in Buffalo.
June in Buffalo Photograph Collection
A selection of images from the June in Buffalo festivals is available through University at Buffalo Libraries Digital Collections.